他們說勝者書寫歷史
They say that history is written by the victors.
而保護傘公司的歷史
This then is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
就是由科學家詹姆士·馬爾庫斯教授所執筆
Formed by a crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
馬爾庫斯有個年幼的女兒叫艾麗西亞
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia.
她患有早衰癥  這種致命疾病會逐漸消耗人的體力
Afflicted with "Progeria". A progressive fatal wasting disease.
早衰即過早衰老  等艾麗西亞25歲的時候
Progerie caused premature aging. By the time she was 25,
她的身體會老得和90歲老人一樣
Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
馬爾庫斯竭盡全力去救她 但希望渺茫
Marcus was driven to save her but the odds seemed impossible.
在瘋狂製造藥劑的同時 艾麗西亞的父親還會記錄她的日常
Even as he worked desperately to create a cure, the young girl's father would record his daughter;
她的聲音 她的樣貌  欲使她永生
Her voice, her likeness. Saving her from posterity.
但之後便取得了突破
But then the breakthrough came.
馬爾庫斯發現了T病毒
Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
注射入體內 它會偵測並修復體內受損細胞
Once injected, it would detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
這就是個奇跡
It was a miracle.
艾麗西亞·馬爾庫斯得救了
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
T病毒得到廣泛應用
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications.
被用於上千種不同的疾病
Treating a thousand different diseases.
人們彷彿在一夜間迎來了新的紀元
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
對於感染 病痛 或是衰老再沒了懼怕
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
但事實並非如此
But it was not to be...
T病毒有著一些不可預見的副作用
But the T-Virus has a certain unforseen side effects.
先生 先生  快過來
Sir, sir! Over here.
他快沒呼吸了
He's not breathing.
第一個不死之人誕生了
The first of the undead was born.
此次事故被迅速掩蓋
The incident was quickly covered up.
事情尚未完全平息 詹姆士·馬爾庫斯卻和他的商業合夥伴亞歷山大·艾薩克斯博士激烈地爭吵起來
In the aftermath, James Marcus argued furiously with his business partner, Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
我不在乎會付出多少代價  我們必須終止該項目
I don't care how much it costs. We have to close the program down.
詹姆士 我們會身敗名裂的
James, we're gonna be ruined.
我已下定決心
My mind is made up.
躺回床上去 艾麗西亞  我和你爹在聊天呢
Off to bed Alicia. Your father and I are just talking.
快去
Go on.
艾薩克斯教授便成了他合作夥伴遺孤及其半個公司的監護人
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child and her half of the company.
因高尚情懷而建的公司 如今已墮落為貪婪與權欲的信徒
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals had been seduced completely by greed and power.
為了控制保護傘公司帶來的巨大利益
To help him control the now vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
艾薩克斯博士編了一套強大的人工智能程序
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾薩克斯將電腦的交互界面做成艾麗西亞·馬爾庫斯的樣子
Isaacs used the likeness of Alicia Marcus for the computer's interface.
並稱這台電腦為紅後
Isaacs called the computer, the Red Queen.
十年前 浣熊市發生了洩露  T病毒從蜂巢的地下實驗室洩露了出去
Then ten years ago, in Raccoon City, there was an outbreak. The T-Virus escaped from an underground laboratory called the Hive.
美國政府試圖通過投放炸彈來阻止這次洩露
The American government attempted to contain the outbreak by detonatng bomb.
炸彈炸毀了浣熊市
It devastated Raccoon City.
卻沒能阻止空氣傳播的病毒
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
病毒洩露 沒到幾天就在世界範圍內傳播開來
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
人類對此束手無策
Human kind was brought to its knees.
最終 肩負最後及最大希望的人們決心在華盛頓特區背水一戰
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
但我們並未認識到我們已經深陷圇圄
But we didn't realized that what we had walked into was a trap.
我是愛麗絲 這是我的故事
My name is Alice and this is my story.
也是我故事的終結
The end of my story.
你好
Hello.
有人活著嗎
Is there anyone alive in here?
你好
Hello?
你是來幸災樂禍的嗎
You come here to gloat?
我的衛星顯示在地球表面有4472名人類存活
My satellite show, there are 4,472 humans remaining in the surface of the earth.
他們會在接下來的48小時內死亡
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
你想從我這得到什麼
What do you want from me?
想讓我說你贏了嗎  你滅亡了人類
Do you want me to say that you've won? You've wiped out humanity.
不 恰恰相反  我想讓你阻止我
No, quite the opposite. I want you to stop me.
小心身後
Behind you.
身手不錯
Nicely done.
我不相信你
I don't trust you.
介於我們之間的恩怨  你信我才怪呢
Given our history, I'd be surprised if you did.
但是你若不干涉 這次病毒爆發將無法阻止
But unless you intervene, this flowtill will be complete.
屆時將無人倖免
There will be no survivors.
我怎麼才能幫助他們
How can I possibly help them?
保護傘公司開發了氣態病毒抗體
Umbrella developed an airborne anti virus.
如果傳播出去將會消滅T病毒以及任何感染T病毒的生物
If released it would destroy the T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
- 那就能終結這一切？  - 準確的說 是的
- all this could end?  - precisely
哪能找到這種病毒抗體？
where is this anti-virus?
就保存在浣熊市地下的蜂巢
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
你為什麼要幫我
Why would you help me?
我的編程不允許我毀掉保護傘公司
My programming will not allow me to harm the Umbrella Corporation.
但你不受約束
But you are bound by no set of constraints.
你要與保護傘公司為敵  與製造你的人為敵嗎 為什麼
You'd turn against Umbrella? Against the people who created you? Why?
在48小時內趕到浣熊市的蜂巢  你自會找到答案
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive. And then you'll have your answer.
你說的話 我一個字都不信
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
的確  但我有你特別想要的東西
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
什麼
What is that?
向威斯克復仇
Revenge. Wesker.
他將你引至華盛頓  假裝使你恢復力量
He led you all here to Washington. He pretended he gave you your powers back.
然後再背叛你
And then, he betrayed you.
他現身在何處
Where is he?
他就在蜂巢
He just landed at the Hive.
我正在重設你的手錶
I'm resetting your watch.
倒計時開始
The clock is ticking.
愛麗絲 我們十年前在蜂巢的失敗導致了現今的一切 就當是贖罪吧
Alice, 10 years ago in the Hive. We both failed. We let this happen. Make it right.
你們就這點能耐嗎
Is that all you got?
愛麗絲
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢
10 years ago in the Hive.
將不會有倖存者
There will be no survivors.
這是什麼地方
What is this place?
我在哪兒
Where am I?
說話啊
answer me
你們怎麼回事
What's wrong with you?
安靜
Be quiet.
這是誰幹的
Who did this?
我說了 安靜
Quiet. I told you.
閉嘴
Silence.
最終你還是醒了
So you're awake at last.
我曾手刃了你
I killed you.
但我還活著
Yet here I am.
克隆體  我殺的是你的克隆體
A clone. I killed your clone.
你和你的克隆體們
You'd be most troublesome to me.
真是我的大麻煩呢
You and your sisters.
現在我終於捉到了你
Now I have you.
清除你們的任務早該在一年多以前就完成了 但是你拖累了我們
The cleansing operation should have finished over a year ago, but you slowed us down.
以至於我不得不自控
So much so that I was obliged to take command of myself.
你能夠終結這一切  為什麼不這麼做
You could end all of this. Why haven't you?
有意思
interesting
有人給你透露了點實情 是吧
Someone told you something, didn't they?
別急 很快你就會上趕著來告訴我的
Ah well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
她沒有信仰  我們該怎麼處置沒有信仰的人
She's an unbeliever. What do we do with unbelievers?
扔出去
Cast her out!
扔出去 扔出去
Cast her out! Cast her out! Cast her out!
動手
Come on!
扔出去 扔出去
Cast her out! Cast her out! Cast her out!
上帝借洪水之力來掃蕩地球
The Lord created a flood to cleanse the earth.
下了40天日夜不休的大雨  相比我們的方法耗時略長 但效果相同
40 days and 40 nights of rain. Our method is taken a little longer but the result will be the same.
我們即將迎來的是一個正直且純淨的世界
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
再過12個多小時 我們就會抵達浣熊市
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
這麼久 我擔心你體力跟不上呢
I doubt even you can run for that long.
告訴我你知道的一切
I want to know what you know.
她挺不住的時候再喊我
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
威斯克
Wesker.
艾薩克斯博士
Dr. Isaacs.
看看我在路邊找到了什麼
Look what I found on the roadside.
看來你華盛頓任務並沒有那麼成功嘛
It would appear your mission to Washington was less successful that you made head.
- 不可能  - 希望你沒留下其他禍根
- impossible  - I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
還有件事
There's something else.
我覺得她知道了以空氣為載體的病毒抗體
I think she knows about the airborne anti virus.
怎麼可能
How can that be?
目前我還不清楚  但我們在去浣熊市的路上抓到了她
I don't know...yet.  But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City.
她去那兒還能為了什麼
Why else should she be headed there?
把蜂巢的安保等級調到最高  不允許任何人進出  愛麗絲打算開口的時候我會跟你說的
Raise the security level of the Hive to maximum. No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
上帝與你同在
God go with you.
你也聽到了  把安保等級調到最高
You heard him. Security level to maximum.
遵命
As you wish.
你們去上面看看
Get up there and check it out.
放了我
Release me.
打開艙門
Open them.
好的 好的
Alright, alright.
你沒有騎這輛摩托車的權限 看你往哪逃
You can't use it. You can't escape.
臥槽
Oh Jesus.
先生 她逃了
Sir, she's gone.
目標離我們72英里 正朝我們逼近
Target is 72 miles and closing.
封鎖整個蜂巢
Lock down the Hive.
準備好防禦措施
Prepare defensive measures.
並且提醒我們在浣熊市的操作員
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
空氣傳播的病毒抗體
Airborne anti virus.
48小時
Under  48 hours.
趕到蜂巢
Make it to the Hive.
放開他  趕緊放開他
Let him go! Let him go now!
- 道客我早就跟你說了 - 冷靜 克裏斯汀 - 我早說過你是錯的
- I told you Doc - calm down Christian  - I told you you were wrong.
冷靜點
Calm down.
我們剛有機會的時候就應該把她殺了
We should've killed her when we had the chance.
還是把武器放下吧 不然她會開槍殺了我們倆
Put it down please before she tries to shoot the both of us.
這裏面是什麼
What's in this?
純腎上腺素  我需要你醒過來
Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake.
為什麼
Why?
在你來的方向 有什麼東西過來了  一個很龐大的東西
There's something coming. In the same direction you came. Something big.
放開他  放下武器
Let him go! Put it down now!
愛麗絲
Alice?
保護傘公司在阿卡迪亞抓住了我
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
他們把我帶去了一個叫蜂巢的地方 後來我們擺脫了防守 殺了飛行員 然後飛機墜到這了
We were headed somewhere called the Hive. Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
道客和其他人把我從廢墟中拖了出來  我的命是他們給的
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash. I owe them my life.
道客  看東部方向 有東西朝這來
Doc! There to the east, still headed our way.
你知道那是什麼嗎
You know what it is?
保護傘公司的艾薩克斯博士
Umbrella. Dr. Isaacs.
我以為你殺了他
I thought that you killed him.
我也那麼以為
I thought so too.
要不了幾個小時 他和他的喪屍軍團就能到這了
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
我們怎麼辦
What do we do?
我們特麼為什麼要問她
Why the hell are we asking her?
她就是一個陌生人  我們不應該信她
She's a stranger. We shouldn't trust her.
道客 你他媽別碰我
Don't you touch me Doc.
放下武器
Put it down.
你放下武器
You put it down.
老兄 聽我說 你覺得自己應該是總指揮不代表你就是總指揮
Hey, look at me. Cause you think you should be in charge doesn't make it so.
道客 聽著  你們會後悔的  你們所有人都會後悔的
You listen to me Doc. You're gonna regret it. All of you. All of you!
我得趕去蜂巢  你必須帶著大家離開這
I have to get to the Hive. You have to get this people out of here.
這裏有小孩 傷者還有老人  他們在開闊的馬路上哪有生存的可能
There are children, injured, the elderly. Now what chance they have in the open road?
總比他們在這活下去的幾率大
Better than they have here.
這座建築很安全
This building is secure.
對喪屍而言這可能很安全 但艾薩克有裝甲車 火箭筒  還有其他能瞬間撕裂這棟建築的重量級武器
Maybe from the undead but Isaacs have armored vehicles, rocket launchers, heavy ordinance that can tear this place wide open.
道客
Doc!
她到底怎麼了
So what happened to her?
她碰到我們在角落設的陷阱了  本來這些陷阱是為了防喪屍的
she was open one of the traps, made out of . They are intended for the undead.
這是什麼
What is this?
我們這的特色  每個人都喝過
Speciality on the house. everyone feed it on time.
我憑什麼信任你
Why should I trust you?
給
Here.
道客  你得出去看看  大家都很害怕 而且克裏斯汀在幫倒忙
Doc? You need to get out there. People are scared and Christian is not helping.
你得讓大家知道發生了什麼
You need to let people know what's happening.
那好  我得走了  對了 你的朋友不會有事的
Okay. I gotta go. Hey, your friend's gonna be okay.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你知道嗎 我和他
You know he and I...
我注意到了
I noticed.
蜂巢裏到底有什麼
So what's in the Hive?
保護傘公司研發出了解藥  一種空氣傳播的病毒抗體
Umbrella developed a cure. An airborne anti virus.
它能殺死所有T病毒的宿主
It'll destroy anything infected with the 6-Virus on contact.
誰告訴你的
Who told you this?
紅後
The Red Queen.
你居然相信她
And you believed her?
萬一我們真的能結束這場災難呢
What if we could end all this?
那你怎麼辦  他們給你也注射了T病毒
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
你打算散佈的這種反病毒會殺死你
You release this anti virus, its going kill you.
破釜沉舟 義無反顧
Whatever it takes
愛麗絲 我不
Alice, I'm not...
你知道我是對的
You know I'm right.
好吧
All right.
我們先擊敗艾薩克斯  救完這些人 我們再一起去蜂巢
We stop Issacs here. We save these people and we go together.
我們時間不多了  開始吧
We don't have long. Let's get to it.
你們還有什麼其他的防禦武器嗎
What else do you have for defense?
我們沒有特別多的槍支 但我們有很充足的汽油供應
Not too many firearms but we have a big supply of gasoline.
給 你需要一件武器
Here, you need a weapon.
我們現在都給她槍了
We're giving her a gun now?
克裏斯汀 別激動
Take it easy Christian.
老兄 你願意卸下你的警戒心 可我不願意
You can let your guard down if you want man, I don't intend to.
我騎著摩托剛到這的時候 有個人一直在盯著我
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
他本來能開一槍提醒我你們設下的陷阱 但他沒開槍
It could have called out to fire to shot to warn me about the trap but it didn't.
什麼意思
what are you saying?
當心有人背後捅刀子
Watch your back.
艾薩克斯博士 看樣子她又成功逃脫了 而且他們很多人還活著
So Dr. Isaacs, seems you let her slip through your fingers. A lot remains of them.
可別忘了你是在和誰說話 她在哪
don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
浣熊市的安置區  有線人匯報說她正為一場戰鬥做準備
The settlements in Raccoon City. Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
很好 我一個小時後就會到那
Good, I'll be there in an hour.
就是這樣  繼續推
That's it. Keep moving.
我們需要所有的汽油桶  放在那
Need all the gasoline cans. Over there.
克萊爾說是你建的這個
Claire said you built this.
是的 沒錯
Yeah, that's right.
這原來是一台窗戶清洗機  我改裝了一下
This used to be a window washer. I made a couple of changes.
你從哪學來的
Where did you learn to do that?
我爸原來經營一家汽車拆修廠  我很討厭那  誰知道呢  大概當時還是有在認真看吧
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it. Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all.
很好 因為我還想讓你再繼續改裝一下
Good, because I'm gonna need you to make a few more changes to this thing.
準備好武器  填好高爆彈藥  不准留下活口
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds. No survivors.
他來了
He's here.
他們來了  快關上大門
They're coming. Close the gate!
我的老天  這簡直是一個軍隊
My god! It's an army.
我們該怎麼辦
What are we gonna do?
是啊 我們該怎麼辦
Yeah, what are we gonna do?
我們要殺光他們所有人
We're gonna kill every last one of them.
準備開火
Prepare to fire.
大家準備好
Get ready!
點火
Lighten  up!
開炮
Fire!
我草他媽
Damn her.
再次填裝
Reload.
全面停止進攻
Close it up. Full stop.
把誘餌放出去
Release the bait.
那有一位倖存者  打開大門
There's a survivor. Open the gate.
打開大門
Open the gate!
開火
Open fire!
給她打掩護
Keep them off her.
準備第二發
Mark ready 2.
開炮
Fire!
克萊爾 道客  快去那把她帶進來
Claire, Doc! Get out there, bring her in.
加把勁
Come on.
等等
Wait.
她快到了
She's almost there.
開火
Fire.
該死
Damn you.
關門現在
Close the gate now.
克萊爾 它們已經突破大門了
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克萊爾
Claire!
開火
Fire.
瑞瑟爾 現在
Razor, now!
好 你們聽見她說什麼了  推
Right, you heard her. Push!
從大門撤退  撤回到路障那裏
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
看起來她好像沒上鉤
Looks like she's out of tricks.
向頂上射擊
Target the roof.
所有人趴下
Everybody get down!
趴下
Down!
愛麗絲 我們到達路障了
Alice, we're at the barricades.
克萊爾 你們得把它們阻止在那裏
Claire, you have to hold them there.
道客小心
Doc!
愛麗絲 我們撐不住了
Alice, we can't hold on much longer.
現在撤退
Get out of there now.
補給火力  現在
Back up! Now!
全力向她射擊
Bring all guns to her.
開火
Fire.
她在哪
Where is she?
她去哪了
where did she go?
找到她
Find her.
關閉通風口
Close the vents now!
別開槍
Don't shoot.
你很快但你還不夠聰明
You're fast but you're not too smart.
求你別開槍
Don't shoot please.
他在哪
Where is he?
那邊
That way.
節約點子彈
Save your ammo.
這裏喪屍太多了
There's too many of these things out there.
我來處理
I'll take care of it.
前進
Move out!
走吧
Let's go.
敬請享受你的旅程吧
Enjoy the ride.
夥計們
Guys.
你說
Go.
有些東西你們得來看看
There's something here you gotta see.
還有兩波喪屍衝我們來了 地平線那裏一波
Two more armies of undead headed straight for us, there on the horizon.
另一波從那過來的
The second over there.
我們用來防禦的汽油已經用光了
We're out of gasoline for defenses.
我們必須趕到蜂巢 這是我們唯一的機會
We have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
我和你一起去
I'm coming with you.
算我一個
Count me in.
我也去
Me too.
還有我
And me.
所以我之前誤會你了
So I was wrong about you.
你哪裏也不能去
There's no way you're going.
我們知道前方危機四伏 我們想加入進來  拜託了
We know the pit, we wanna come. Please.
帶上些工具 你們會用上的
Grab some gear, you're gonna need it.
那裏
There.
那是什麼
What is it?
一部分被爆炸暴露的蜂巢  這兒就是我們的入口
Part of the Hive that was exposed by the blast. That's our way in.
行動
Let's move.
我來領隊
I'll take point.
啟動安全監測
Activate security measures now.
蜂巢安保系統已完全啟動並自動操作
Hive security fully activated and automated.
不
No.
解除自動操作  我要親自操作防禦系統
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
我來控制防禦系統的話將更有效率
The defenses would be more efficient if I retain the control of them.
是麼
Really?
我好像記得她上次活著離開了這裏呢
I seemed to remember last time she was here she walked out alive.
同樣的錯誤我不想犯第二次
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
如你所願  蜂巢防禦系統由你全權掌控
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
放出地獄犬
Unleash the Cerberus.
地獄犬準備完畢
Cerberus are in play.
這一切爆發之前 你是一個人嗎
You have someone before all this?
有沒有丈夫  家庭
Husband? Family?
不記得了
Can't remember.
怎麼可能
How's that possible?
我醒來的時候一切已經開始了
I woke up just when all this was starting.
之前的事情不怎麼記得了  有時候我感覺這就是生活的全部 亡命天涯 大開殺戒
Can't recall much before that. Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life,running, killing.
那是什麼
What is it?
有東西在跟著我們
Something stalking us.
- 你確定嗎 - 我就是幹這行的
- Are you sure? - This is what I do.
快  快跑
Run. Run fast!
跟上
Come on!
所有人都還好嗎
Is everyone okay?
走這邊
It's this way.
就在我們後面
Right behind us.
它們為什麼停下了
Why'd they stop?
- 也許它們害怕了 - 害怕什麼
- Maybe they're scared.- Scared of what?
下面肯定有什麼東西讓它們害怕
Whatever's down there.
封鎖蜂巢
Seal the Hive.
我們走
Let's go.
愛麗絲
Alice!
你還好嗎
You okay?
我的彈夾已經用完一半了
My mag's half empty.
我把槍丟在湖那裏了
Lost my guns at the lake.
我只剩下槍膛裏的子彈
I only have one round left.
和一個備用彈匣了
One spare mag and I'm out.
沒有槍 沒有彈藥  我們在這兒到底怎麼辦
No guns, no ammo. What the hell are we gonna do down here?
愛麗絲 那束光是怎麼回事
Alice? What's with the lights?
這個區域被毀了  電力不穩定
This part of the Hive is damaged. The powers erratic.
這個 拿著
Here, take this.
聽著
Hey, look.
你之前問我為什麼與保護傘公司反目 我承諾要告訴你答案
You asked why I would turned against Umbrella and I promised you an answer.
T病毒爆發過後不久 一份機密文件傳到了我的數據庫裏
Soon after the T-Virus was released, a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
那是病毒爆發17個月以前 一份保護傘公司高層會議的視頻記錄
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella high command. Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred.
我們今天坐在一起 討論的不只是公司的前景 還有人類的宿命
We're here today, not just to talk about the future of this company. We're here to talk about this destiny.
世界的終結
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
我們站在末日的邊緣 經歷著無法治癒的疾病
We stand on the brink of Armageddon. Diseases for which we have no cure.
原教主義自求毀滅 對於核武器我們又束手無策
Fundamentalist stage who called for our destruction. Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
即便我們度過這一切難關 還是會有其他不可避免的威脅
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters, we face other even more inevitable threats.
全球變暖將在80年內融化兩極的冰蓋 淹沒地球上百分之90可居住的區域
Global warming will melt the polarized caps within 80 years, flooding 90 percent of all habitable areas on earth.
要不了50年 食物產量就會無法供養瘋狂增長的人口 饑荒和戰爭無可避免
Unchecked population growth will overtake food production in less than 50 years leading to famine and war.
這不是猜想 而是事實  殊途同歸 我們的世界終將毀滅
This is not conjecture, this is fact. One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
問題是 我們會隨之滅絕嗎
Now the question is...will we end with it?
你有什麼好的建議嗎
What do you propose?
我建議我們按照自己的方式親手毀滅這個世界
I propose that we end the world but on our terms.
一場精心策劃的世界末日
An orchestrated apocalypse.
清除地球上的人口 但完整保留其基礎設施和能源
One that will cleanse the earth of its population but leave its infrastructure and resources intact.
這一想法已經成功實施過
It's been done once before with great success.
被選中的少數人將在安全的地下平安度過這場災難 而不是創世紀裏所說的諾亞方舟上
The chosen few will ride out the storm not in an ark as in the book of Genesis but in safety underground.
末日結束後 我們將在一個淨化過的地球上重建屬於我們的輝煌
And when it's over, we will emerge unto a cleansed earth. One that we can then reboot in our image.
你要怎麼做到這一切呢
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
救世之法就在我們手中
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
我為你們帶來了 T病毒
I give to you...the T-Virus.
他們是故意洩露它的
They release it deliberately.
這視頻傳進我數據庫的時候 讓我的編程出了點故障
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream, it created a conflict in my programming.
我被創造出來服務保護傘公司 但是我也是珍視人類生命的
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation but I was also programmed to value human life.
艾薩克斯博士允許了病毒洩露  他謀殺了70億人
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape. He murdered over 7 billion people.
我的系統不允許我傷害任何一個保護傘公司的員工
My programming will not allow me to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
我無力阻止艾薩克斯博士 但你卻可以
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs but you are not.
在37分鐘後 人類最後的定居點將會狗帶 無人能夠生還
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements will fall. There will be no survivors.
在這發生之前你必須釋放病毒抗體 否則保護傘公司就贏了
It's imperative that you release the anti virus before this occurs or Umbrella will have won.
還有最後一件事 你面前有一個耳機 戴上它
There's one last thing, there's an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
我無法親自傷害保護傘公司的員工 但我要告訴你 保護傘公司在浣熊市有個線人
I cannot do my actions: harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation but I can tell you that Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
而且這個人很有可能就在你的隊伍裏
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
時間不多了 愛麗絲 你得抓緊
Time is running out Alice. You have to hurry.
很高興見到你 艾薩克斯博士
Glad to see you Dr. Isaacs.
我們覺得上次攻擊之後 無人存活
We didn't think there are any survivors after the last attack.
水
Water.
是的 先生  當然
Yes sir. Of course.
給艾薩克斯博士倒點水
Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
重新開始浣熊市的進程
Then resume course for Raccoon City.
她不在那兒
She's not there.
她去了深井 我們得跟著她
She went to the pit, we have to follow.
我們得去深井
We have to go to the pit.
謝謝
Thank you.
這是哪
What is this place?
這是蜂巢的一個進風口  來吧
It's an air intake for the Hive. Come on.
別啊  真的要去
No. Really?
解除警報
All clear!
快點  電力馬上要恢復了
Hurry up! The powers coming back on.
快啊  咱們走
Hurry! Let's go!
快來
Come on!
有人在監視咱們
Someone's watching us.
把渦輪向反方向旋轉
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
渦輪片正在向反方向旋轉
The plates are going the other way.
我們得離開這兒
We have to get out of here.
渦輪片正向後吸著空氣
The plates are sucking the air backwards.
快點
Come on!
這邊
This way.
我們得快
We have to hurry.
等等
Wait!
咱們走
Let's go.
萊瑟爾
Razor?
你沒事吧
You okay?
沒事
Yeah
咱們走
Let's go.
嗨
Hey!
這他媽是什麼
What the hell is that?
生化武器 這是個人類
Bioweapon. This one's human.
你看見克萊爾了嗎
Have you seen Claire?
沒有
No.
萊瑟爾呢
Razor?
他沒有挺過來
He didn't make it.
快點 我們得抓緊了
Come on. We have to hurry.
照這樣下去 她7分鐘之後就能到達這了
If the target continues on her present course, she'll be here in 7 minutes.
把他們喚醒
Wake them.
除非有極度緊急的情況 否則我不會接受這樣的指令
My instructions aren't to do so. Only in the greatest of emergencies.
把他們喚醒
Wake them now.
這是什麼
What is it?
我們得離開這兒
We have to get out of here.
這兒
Here.
我們去切斷電源
We're stopping power.
快沒時間了
Time's running out.
下一步去哪
Where to next?
蜂巢的最後一層就在我們腳下
The final level of the Hive's below us.
我們要怎麼去
How do we get down there?
就像這樣
Like so.
他們是什麼
What are they?
低溫儲存
Cyrogenic storage.
這裏肯定有上千個
Must be thousands of em.
保護傘最高指揮部
The Umbrella high command.
安全地等待著世界末日的結束
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
專為有權的有錢人打造的諾亞方舟
Noah's ark for the rich and powerful.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
幫我一把
Give me a hand.
搞定了嗎
Is it done?
淨化過程完成了嗎
The cleansing process is complete?
沒有
No.
那我為什麼醒了
Then why am I awake?
我們遇到了一個問題
We had a problem.
我試著
I tried...
省省吧
Save your breath.
我知道發生了什麼
I know exactly what's happening.
我們被背叛了
We've been betrayed.
對啊
That's right!
這裏
Over here!
來啊 就是這兒  跟我來
Come on...that's it. Follow me.
這不是那個浪子回頭的女兒嗎
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
咱們走
Let's go.
這不是悔悟回家的女兒嗎
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
壞苗子回來了
The bad seed returns.
這不是悔悟回家的女兒嗎
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
別杵在那兒 進來
Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
畢竟你只有9分鐘來拯救世界
After all you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
你是真身嗎
You're really him?
首先呢 我需要你放下武器
First things first. I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
我憑什麼聽你的
Why would I wanna do that?
這就是你想要的 不是嗎
This is what you're after, yes?
病毒抗體 這一切的解藥
The anti virus. The cure to all this.
可是解藥只有一瓶哦
Well, there's only one vial.
況且我們在地下半英里的一個封閉設施裏
And we're half a mile down underground in a sealed facility.
我摔了它 病毒抗體和你無望的夢想 會灰飛煙滅得更早喲
I drop it here and the anti virus goes nowhere and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
乖寶寶
Good girl.
你還沒放下槍
You're still armed.
沒錯
Yes, I am.
克萊爾得多麼失望
Claire would be so disappointed.
幾分鐘後 克萊爾會和其他你認識的人一樣死翹翹
A few minutes, Claire would be dead along with everybody else you know.
真棒
That's sweet.
抱歉 我的甜心
Sorry, my love.
離武器和引爆器遠點
Move away from the weapon and the detonator.
她把爆炸物放在最高指揮部的低溫管處 我會解除它們
She place explosives in the high command cryo tubes, I'll disarm them.
謝謝 道客 你做得很好
Thank you. You've done well Doc.
別掙扎了 你不會成功的
Don't bother. You don't make it.
無論是碎冰錐玻璃瓶或是鋼筆
To the ice pick, to the decanter or the phantom pen.
至於你的問題 除了幾個克隆體 我就是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克斯博士
And in aswer to your question, yes apart from a few technological upgrades, I am Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
本體
The original.
我在外面遇見的那個 他也覺得自己是本體
The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
當然 我們就是這麼設計的
Of course he did, that's how they're designed.
我們一直不斷努力嘗試 不懼怕時間甚至死亡
We always try harder and fight longer even to the death.
只要他們覺得自己是本體
As long as they think they're the real thing.
畢竟 誰也不願意知道自己只是一副毫無價值的仿製品 就像你一樣
After all, who wants to know they're just a poor imitation of a worthless copy. Which brings us to you.
不
No.
得了 你不會以為自己是本體吧
Oh come on, you thought you were the original?
多美妙啊
How delicious.
不 我懷疑她還是有榮譽感的
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
艾麗西亞·馬爾庫斯 我老搭檔詹姆士的女兒  保護傘公司的共同所有人 我身邊一根痛苦的刺
Alicia Marcus, daughter of my old partner, James. Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation and a painful thorn in my side.
一根我現在想要拔除的刺
One I now intend to remove.
沒時間了愛麗絲 你必須馬上殺了他
Time is running out Alice. You must kill him soon.
我也很高興見到你 艾麗西亞
It's good to see you too Alicia.
馬爾庫斯為了救她發明了T-病毒 但效果並不持久 我已經為她的死等了很久
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her but the effects didn't last but I've been waiting years for her to die.
我以為我不是克隆人
I thought I'm not a clone.
真的麼
Really?
那為什麼你對你的童年 你的父母會毫無記憶
Why is it you could remember nothing of your childhood. Your father? Your mother?
喪失了記憶罷了
Memory loss.
不 你沒有記憶 因為你沒有人生
No, you have no memory because you have no life.
我們十年前在蜂巢創造了你之前 你什麼都沒有
Nothing before the mansion when we created you 10 years ago.
我知道我是誰
I know who I am.
我可不這麼覺得
I don't think so.
你只不過是一個斷了線的木偶 四處瞎逛了一會兒就覺得自己是個真人了 可你不是
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut and then you wandered around for a little while thinking you're a real girl but you're not
你只不過是個聰明的仿製品 一個副本 比副本更麻煩
Your just a clever imitation. A facsimile. A rather troublesome one than that.
你騙我
You're lying to me.
他並沒有騙你
I'm afraid he's not.
你是照著她的樣子被創造出來的  就像我一樣
You are created in her image. As was I.
我的長相和聲音都是艾麗西亞·馬庫斯的父親根據童年時期的她創造的
My likeness and voice were based on childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus made by her father.
你的基因是根據她的DNA構造的 並被調整以防止曾折磨她的兒童早衰老化癥
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA, tweak to avoid the Progerio aging disease that afflicted her.
我是兒童時代的她  你則是成年的她
I'm the child she was. You are the woman she would have been.
不 你比我要好太多 是我任由自己變弱
No, you are so much better than I ever could be. I let this happen.
我曾經很虛弱
I was weak.
你不能變成那樣
You cannot afford to be.
艾麗絲 沒時間了
Time is running out Alice.
啊 真感人
Ahh, that's touching.
婊子三人組 因仇恨團結在一起
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
但這對你沒什麼任何好處  我總是會先你一步 你改變不了任何事 也救不了任何人
Well that wont do you any good. I'll be ahead of you in every step of the way. You change nothing. You've saved no one.
這個世界依舊會被肅清 保護傘公司會是最終的贏家
The world will still be cleansed and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
唯一不同的是 我再也不用聽你那些正義的牢騷了
The only difference is, I no longer have to listen to your self righteous whining.
當你將文件上傳到紅後的數據庫裏時 你就已經背叛了公司
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream, you turned against the corporation.
當董事會剩下的人醒了 你就會被換下
When the rest of the board awake, you will be replaced.
然後我將全權接管
And I will assume complete control.
我仍然有公司百分之五十的股份
I still own 50 percent of this company.
你又準備拿它做什麼呢
And what do you intend to do with that?
你只是公司的共有者
You are co-owner of this corporation.
而威斯克呢  威斯克只是個僱員
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
我不用聽從你的命令 我只忠於他
I don't have to take your orders, my loyalties are with him.
我知道 阿爾伯特·威斯克 你被炒了
I know. Albert Wesker, you're fired.
你怎麼知道是我做的
How did you know it was me?
因為你還活著
You're still alive.
拜託 我當時沒有任何選擇  是他們逼我幹的
Hey, please. It wasn't like I have any choice. They made me do it.
別慌  我不會殺你的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna kill you.
克萊爾 是我啊
Claire, it's me.
對不起
Sorry.
求你
Please.
親愛的
My love.
別別別
No no no.
如果你一直不按下這個扣板 你就一直縱容保護傘公司的夢想不死
If you keep this trigger unpressed, you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
早知當初我應該在華盛頓殺了你
I should have killed you in Washington.
是啊
Yeah.
他只需要再背叛你幾分鐘
He only has to deviate you for another few minutes.
人類最後的村落就會消失了
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
我們需要攔住他 然後以最快的方式到達地球表面
We need an intercept path and a fastest way to the surface.
已經完成了
Already done.
如果你釋放了病毒抗體 它就會殺死所有被T病毒感染的有機體  你知道這對你而言意味著什麼吧
If you release the anti virus, it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus. You know what that means don't you? For you?
我知道
I know.
艾麗絲 你不能這麼做
Alice, you can't.
我別無選擇
I don't have a choice.
一定還有其他的解決辦法
There has to be another way.
你知道這是唯一的辦法
You know there isn't.
只剩四分鐘零三十三秒 你得抓緊了
4 minutes and 33 seconds left, you have to hurry.
幫幫我
Help me.
你不需要幫助 威斯克
You don't need help Wesker.
你快死了  習慣就好
You're dying. Just get on with it.
我是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克斯博士  啟動DNA和聲紋身份驗證
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs. Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
身份已確認
Identity confirmed.
安全系統啟動 取消4365號的控制權
Confirm security override 4365.
已取消
Override confirmed.
現在自動離線 然後將一切功能交予我單獨控制
Well now take yourself offline and place all functions under my sole control.
遵命 正在關機
As you wish, shutting down now.
艾薩克斯博士 你和保護傘公司的高層
Dr. Isaacs, you and the Umbrella high command.
怎樣
Yes?
你們都會死在下面
You're all going to die down here.
你的小夥伴也幫不了你了
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你逃不掉了
You can't run anymore.
我並沒有逃
I wasn't running.
你就這點本事了嗎
Is that all you got?
如果就這點本事 我就得殺了你
Cause if it is, I'm gonna have to kill you.
我們已經玩得夠久了 你和我
We've played a long game you and I.
但現在一切都結束了
But now it's over.
是啊
Yes.
是的
Yes it is.
我創造了你
I made you.
是的
Yeah.
你犯了個大錯
Big mistake.
克萊爾
Claire.
快走 趁著還有時間
Go! While there's still time.
走  我就跟在你的後面
Go, I'll be right behind you.
你沒時間了
Your time's up.
艾麗絲  我帶他們來了
Alice  I've brought them here.
我為你把他們帶來了
I've brought them for you.
你是誰
What the hell are you?
我是你啊 傻瓜
I'm you, you idiot.
不 不
No. No.
不 這不可能
No, that's not possible.
我是真的你
The real you.
不可能
No.
騙子  討厭的傢伙
Liar! Abomination!
骯髒的傢伙
Filthy!
我才是我  他不是我
I'm me. He's not me.
你做到了 艾麗絲 艾麗絲
You did it Alice. Alice.
你做到了
You did it!
為什麼我還活著
Why am I still alive?
我不知道
I don't know.
發生了什麼
What happened?
艾薩克斯死後 我便可以重新自動上線 阻止對剩下人類安置點的攻擊
When Isaacs died, I could bring myself back online and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements.
是你拯救了他們
You saved them.
為什麼我還活著
Why am I still alive?
病毒抗體只摧毀了你體內的T病毒  它並沒有傷害你體內健康的細胞
The anti virus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body. It didn't harm the healthy cells.
你現在已經不受病毒感染了
You are now free of infection.
你說我會死掉 你和艾麗西亞都這樣說 你們騙了我
You thought I would die, you and Alicia. You lied to me.
我們得知道你是否願意做出犧牲 捨棄自己的生命去拯救大家
We had to know if you are willing to make the sacrifice. To give up your life for others.
保護傘公司裏沒有第二個人會這樣做了
This was something no one at Umbrella would have done.
艾麗西亞·馬庫斯是對的
Alicia Marcus was right about you.
你是他們中最棒的
You were better than all of them.
我也曾是其中一員 我是被保護傘公司創造的
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
我只是他們的一個工具
Just an instrument for them.
不 你遠超出了他們的預料
No, you became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
克隆人變得比人類更人類
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
你只剩一步未邁出了
And you have one more step to make.
你什麼意思
What do you mean?
艾麗西亞死前為你上傳了她的記憶
Before she died, Alicia uploaded her memories for you.
記憶裏是你從未有過的童年
The childhood you never had.
正好可以和你擁有 而她無法經歷的成年記憶相結合
Combined with the woman she could never become.
T病毒在地球上
When the T-Virus spread across the earth.
以噴氣客機為載體
It did so at the speed of the modern world.
很快便散播開了
Carried by jet liners across the globe.
病毒抗體在空中 隨風傳播
The anti virus is airborne, spread by the winds.
也許要花上幾年它才能散播到地球的每個角落
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the earth.
不到那時 我的工作就不會結束
Until then, my work here is not done.
我的名字叫艾麗絲
My name is Alice.
你好 愛麗絲
西
浣熊市
使用者未經授權
保護傘之家
歡迎來到浣熊市
伸冤在我 我必報應
保護性搏鬥軟體
生命維持：危急
系統故障
生命維持：0%
{\bord0\shad0\fscx0\fsp2\t(22,300,1,\fscx90)\t(1000,1100,1,\fry90)\c&H7F7A6D&\pos(649,46)}生化危機6
EF字幕組
翻譯 傳承者 橙子 伊塔 Riki 珍珠草
校對 鼠大
監製 衛溪
特效 豆包